so let's discuss what types of
benchmarks do we have out there we can
have real applications they are the most
representative of real applications but
they're also the most difficult to set
up on a new machine so for example if
we're building a new computer system we
may not be able to run a full fledged
operating system there and have all the
you know graphics cards and hard drives
etcetera etcetera connected so it may
not be possible to run for example a web
browser or a database on this machine
yet next we can have application kernels
we find the most time-consuming part of
an application usually a loop of some
sort and we isolate just that loop and
say that this is what are we gonna use
for testing performance of machines that
way we don't have to run a full-blown
application all we have to do is find a
way to run just the kernels on the new
machine that we're testing but sometimes
running a reasonable sized kernel is
still too difficult for example in the
early stages of prototyping a machine
when we may not even have a compiler for
example so the next class of benchmarks
are the so-called synthetic benchmarks
they're usually designed to behave
similarly to some type of a kernel but
to be much simpler to compile pretty
much they're kind of the abstract of a
kernel and finally we can compare
machines not based on how well they
perform on some actual code that they're
running but purely based on peak
performance in theory how many
instructions per second should this
machine be able to execute usually peak
performance is only good for marketing
doesn't tell us very much about the
actual performance of the machine
synthetic benchmarks are usually very
good for design studies of potential new
machines but they are not very good for
actually reporting performance to others
so we can use this just to see how well
do we expect a design to behave so that
we can choose among multiple possible
designs once we actually build a machine
we can use for example kernels to test
the performance of a prototype and
finally we should be using real
applications if we are comparing our
machines that we're trying to for
example sell to somebody